RG 009:007, Indian Litigation Files
Connecticut State Library
Indian Litigation files
1666-2008
bulk 1965-2008
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Office of the Attorney General. Special Litigation Department
24.25 cubic feet
The Office of the Attorney General, Special Litigation Department represents the interests of people of Connecticut in matters related to federal tribal recognition and in litigation involving land claims brought by groups claiming Indian ancestry. Indian Litigation files include: Attorney General; Bureau of Indian Affairs; Eastern Pequot; Golden Hill Paugussetts; Mashantucket Pequot; Mohegan; Nipmuc; Schaghticoke; Webster/Dudley Band of Chaubunagungamaug Nipmuck Indians; National Archives Microfilm; Miscellaneous Microfilm; and Removable Media.
RG009_007
2009-040
Historical Note
The Office of the Attorney General, Special Litigation Department represents the interests of people of Connecticut in matters related to federal tribal recognition and in litigation involving land claims brought by groups claiming Indian ancestry. The department also provides advice and counsel to numerous state agencies regarding issues of Indian law and issues connected to the two federally recognized Indian tribes in Connecticut and the operation of their casinos.
Scope and Content
The records were arranged into 13 series which document Indian Litigation cases. The series include Attorney General, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Eastern Pequot, Golden Hill Paugusetts, Mashantucket Pequot, Mohegan, Nipmuc, Schatigcoke, Webster/Dudley Band of Chaubunagungamaug Nipmuck Indians, National Archives Microfilm, Miscellaneous Microfilm, Removable Media, and Restricted.
Series 1. Attorney General, 1787-2007, consist of correspondence; subject files; press files; and a research notebook.
Series 2. Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1980-2004, contain correspondence and subject files.
Series 3. Eastern Pequot, 1800-2006, consist of legal documents; Bureau of Indian Affairs background material, proposed findings for federal acknowledgment, and technical assistance information; exhibits; correspondence; subject files; press files; and maps showing ancestry, plan of properties, and reservation of the Eastern Tribe of Pequot Indians.
Series 4. Golden Hill Paugussetts, 1708-2006, include Bureau of Indian Affairs correspondence, brief, exhibits, determinations on federal acknowledgment, proposed findings, petitions, and residence analsysis and supplement; legal documents; subject files; correspondence; lobbying reports; clippings; and maps.
Series 5. Mashantucket Pequot, 1800-2007, contain E.P.A. Assesment information; E.P.A. Documents for Land Parcels; Pequot Pharmaceutical Network background information and Attorney General opinions; subject files; correspondence; clippings; public relations announcements; and maps.
Series 6. Mohegan, 1848-2006, include legal documents; Bureau of Indian Affairs petition and respondent brief; E.P.A. correspondence, miscellaneous deeds, and background information; correspondence; subject files; and maps.
Series 7. Nipmuc, circa 1745-2007, consist of legal documents; Bureau of Indian Affairs answer brief, Freedom of Information Act responses, proposed findings, and final determinations on federal acknowledgment; correspondence; subject files; clippings; and a photocopied photograph of Kevin Gover with Norma (?) Fox-Gould and William W. Gould, Sr.
Series 8. Schaghticoke, circa 1666-2006, contain legal documents; Bureau of Indian Affairs comments and summary under the criteria and evidence for proposed finding; reports Supplementing the Petition of the Schaghticoke Tribal Nation of Kent, Connecticut for Federal Acknowledgment; correspondence; and subject files.
Series 9. Webster/Dudley Band of Chaubunagungamaug Nipmuck Indians, circa 1952-2008, include Bureau of Indian Affairs answer and response briefs of the State of Connecticut, Freedom of Information Act requests and responses, proposed findings, and final determination on federal acknowledgment; correspondence; and subject files.
Series 10. National Archives Microfilm, 1722-1906, consist of copies of microfilm from the National Archives and Records Administration.
Series 11. Miscellaneous Microfilm, circa 1797-1815, consist of copies of microfilm from the Georgia Departmetn of Archives and History, and New York Historical Society.
Series 12. Removable Media, 2002, contain two floppy disks on Golden Hill - Bureau of Indian Affairs, Acknowledgment Criteria Charts.
Series 13. Restricted, circa 1959-1994
Arrangement
Series 1. Attorney General, 1787-2007
Series 2. Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1980-2004
Series 3. Eastern Pequot, 1800-2006
Series 4. Golden Hill Paugussetts, 1708-2006
Series 5. Mashantucket Pequot, 1800-2007
Series 6. Mohegan, 1848-2006
Series 7. Nipmuc, circa 1745-2007
Series 8. Schaghticoke, circa 1666-2006
Series 9. Webster/Dudley Band of Chaubunagungamaug Nipmuck Indians, circa 1952-2008
Series 10. National Archives Microfilm, 1722-1906
Series 11. Miscellaneous Microfilm, circa 1797-1815
Series 12. Removable Media, 2002
Series 13. Restricted, circa 1959-1994
Related Material
, Connecticut, Office of the Attorney General.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Office of the Attorney General; Massachusetts. Commission on Indian Affairs; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs. Branch of Acknowledgment and Research; Northeastern Connecticut Council of Governments; Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection; Connecticut. Dept. of Transportation; Connecticut. State Park and Forest Commission; Connecticut Indian Affairs Council; United States. National Archives and Records Administration; United States. Department of the Interior; Georgia. Dept. of Archives and History; New-York Historical Society; Southeastern Connecticut Regional Resources Recovery Authority
Subjects:
Indians of North America -- Connecticut; Indians of North America -- Connecticut -- History; Mohegan Indians; Nipmuc Indians; Pequot Indians; Paugusset Indians; Scaticook Indians
Places:
Connecticut; Massachusetts; Montville (Conn.); Ledyard (Conn.); Uncasville (Conn.); Trumbull (Conn.); North Stonington (Conn.); Stonington (Conn.); Kent (Conn.); Groton (Conn.); Hartford (Conn.); Bridgeport (Conn.)
Persons:
Schaefer, Daniel R.; Anderson, Donnald K.; Lieberman, Joseph I.; Babbitt, Bruce E.; Gover, Kevin, 1955-; Rowland, John G., 1957-; Weicker, Lowell, 1931-; Rell, M. Jodi, 1946-; Sarabia, Ed; Dodier, Grace M.
Document Types:
Briefs (legal documents); Clippings; Correspondence; Floppy disks; Legal Documents; Maps; Notebooks; Photocopies; Publications; Reports
Restrictions on Access
Series 12. Removable Media is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Series 13. Restricted is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records were transferred to the State Library in June 2009.
Container List
- Series 1. Attorney General, 1787-2007; bulk 1990-2007
  - Correspondence, 1990-2002
    - Correspondence - Anderson, Donnald K., Clerk of the United States House of Representatives, 1992 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Attorney General of Virginia, 1994 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Kansas State Gaming Agency, 1998 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Lieberman, Joseph I., 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - National Archives and Records Administration, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Office of the Governor, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Office of the Secretary of State, State of Connecticut, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - Perkins Coie, LLP, 2000 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - Schaefer, Daniel R., 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Senate Indian Affairs Committee, 1998 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - United States Department of Education, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - United States Department of the Interior, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - United States Department of the Interior - Freedom of Information act requests, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - United States Department of Justice - Freedom of Information act requests, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - White House, 2000 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Subject Files, 1787-2006
    - Affidavit forms, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Assistant United States Attorney General opinion, Department of the Interior, Cherokee, circa 1852-1993; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bejamin Hawkins papers finding aid and document request, circa 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs - Federal Register directive, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Congressional bills, photocopies, circa 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Connecticut gambling addiction - Connecticut tribes, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Connecticut State Library document requests and copies, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Crosby memo, 1974 October 17; photocopy (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Department of the Interior documents and solicitor's response re certification, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Effect of state held invalid Prosp. v. Retro. effect, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Election laws of the state of Connecticut, 1930; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, Indian Tribes: Air Quality Planning and Management; final rule, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Federal Bar Association - indian law material, 1992 April 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Government Assistance Almanac, circa 1994-1995; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Henry Knox papers, 1960; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Indian Trade and Intercourse Acts and related statutes, circa 1845-1846; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Interior Department - interpretation and policy re jurisdiction, 1898, 1994; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Intern research, 2001 May-July (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Jeremiah Wadsworth - Wadsworth Collection, Library of Congress, circa 1797-1826; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Johnson's digest, circa 1825; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Law of the case (indians), circa 1981; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Ledyard Pequot overseer, circa 1859; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - List of sources - final determination - Golden Hill Paugussett Tribe, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Lobbying reports, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Manuscripts - Library of Congress, circa 1787-1994; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Mashantucket Pequot billing dispute assessments, 1998-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous indian materials, circa 1956-1993; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous pages of Webster's Dictionary, circa 1828; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous - uncertified congressioanl documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Mohegan agreement, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Mohegan assessment and informal opinion, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Morse report to Secretary of War, circa 1822; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - National Coalition Against Legalized Gambling, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Pendent jurisdiction research, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Pequots - water company, 1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Prucha - great father - Jefferson, circa 1905-1965, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Prucha articles - bibliographic records, circa 1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Recognition congressional materials, circa 1931-1953; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Redistricting, notepad, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Research materials, circa 1852-1997, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
    - Research materials - federal, circa 1846-1973; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Research materials - genealogy, 1995-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Research materials - whether Indian tribes without federal recognition are subject to state and municipal regulations, 2006 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Sources of Connecticut Law, undated; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - State / Attorney General directives, 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - State court jurisdiction, circa 1991; photocopy (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - State of Connecticut Legislative Task Force on Indian Affairs Report to General Assembly, 1989-1990; photocopies (Box 1, Folder 65-66)
    - State Indian reservations and building codes, circa 1978-1992, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Stay, circa 1926-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - A Study Concerning the Effects of Legalized Gambling on the Citizens of the State of Connecticut, 1997 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Summary Under the Criteria for the Proposed Finding on the Mashpee Wampanoag Indian Tribal Council, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - Trial referees, circa 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Press Files, 1993-2007
    - Clippings, 1993-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Notebooks, undated
    - Research notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1980-2004
  - Correspondence, 1991-2004
    - Correspondence, 1991-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
  - Subject Files, 1980-2004
    - Decisions, 1982-2004 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
    - Draft Acknowledgment Precedent Manual compiled by Branch of Acknowledgment and Research, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters of deficiency, circa 1980-2003 (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
    - Town of Charlestown, Rhode Island v. Eastern Area Director, Bureau of Indian Affairs, IBIA 89-53-A, 1989 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series 3. Eastern Pequot, 1800-2006; bulk 1965-2006
  - Legal Documents, 1965-2006
    - Affidavit - Rozario, Betty J., 2002 September 20; photocopy (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Amalgamated Industries, Inc. v. the Historic Pequot Tribes, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 23-26)
    - Connecticut, et al. v. Interior, et al., 2001-2006 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Connecticut Indian Affairs Council Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Hearings, Hartford, Connecticut, 1983 September 28, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Information on Paucatuck Eastern Peqout decision of the Connecticut Indian Affairs Council, circa 1976-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Interview of Ashbow Sebastian, 1999 March; photocopied cover sheet (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot appellate court decision, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot appellate court duplicate pleadings, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot appellate court papers, docket number AC 6292, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians, et al. v. Connecticut Council of Indian Affairs, et al. (DHW), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, et al. v. Connecticut Council of Indian Affairs, et al., 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Superior Court duplicate pleadings, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot - Connecticut Indian Affairs Council decision, Exhibit A, circa 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot - Connecticut Indian Affairs Council decision, Exhibit B, circa 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot - Superior Court pleadings - part I, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot - Superior Court pleadings - part II, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Rolling Cloud, A.K.A., et al. v. Gill, Commissioner, et al., United States District Court Case, circa 1965-1993 (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
    - Sebastian, Roy, et al. v. (AMK) Indian Affairs Council of the Department of Environmental Affairs of the State of Connecticut, et al., 1977-1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - State of Connecticut v. United States Department of Interior, Civil Action No. 3:01CV88 (AVC), 2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1813-2002
    - Being an Indian in Connecticut: The Eastern Pequot Tribe of Connecticut's Comments on the Proposed Findings of the Bureau of Acknowledgment and Recognition of March, 2000, 2001 August 2 (Box 4, Folder 2-11)
    - Branch of Acknowledgment and Research analysis, 2002 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Eastern Pequot Tribe summary of file contents pertaining to criteria, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Exhibits in Support of Comments of the State of Connecticut on the Proposed Findings Issued in Response to the Petitions for Tribal Acknowledgment of the Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut and the Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 2001 August 1; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Final determination to acknowledge the Historical Eastern Pequot Tribe, 2002 July (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Freedom of Information requests - release of records, 2001 April 12 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
    - In re Federal Acknowledgment Petition of the Eastern Pequot and Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 2002 September 26 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Overseer reports, circa 1813-1869; photocopies (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Proposed finding for federal acknowledgment of the Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 2000 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Proposed finding for federal acknowledgment of the Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 2000 March 31 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Proposed finding on the recognition of the Eastern Pequot and Paucatuck Eastern Pequot, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
    - Request for reconsideration by the Wiquapaug Eastern Pequot Tribe, 2002 September (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
    - Revised Formal Meeting Agenda Proposed by State of Connecticut on Behalf of the State Interested Parties Concerning the Proposed Findings to Acknowledge the Eastern Pequot and Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Petitions, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Solicitor letter re recuse, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Technical assistance and outline of questions letter, 2001 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Technical assistance meeting transcript, 2000 September 5 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Towns letters to/from Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Exhibits, 1987-1989
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot - Connecticut Indian Affairs Council decision, exhibit c, 1987-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1977-2001
    - Correspondence - Attorney General, 1984-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
    - Correspondence - Attorney General, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 14-20)
    - Correspondence - Barry J. Ward, attorney at law, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence - Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence - Litigation Management Committee, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence - Morgan & Hescock, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians of Connecticut, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Reservation, North Stonington, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence - Rowland, John G., 1995 August 21 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence - Sarabia, Ed, 1977-1992 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence - Schaefer, Daniel R., 1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence - Wilson, Thomas B., circa 1977-1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Subject Files, 1800-2004
    - Eastern Pequot - Interviewing in Social Research, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Eastern Pequot - miscellaneous research, 1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Eastern Pequot - miscellaneous research - including state documents, circa 1900-1990 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Eastern Pequot - voter registration copies, 1906-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - Lobbying reports, 1998-2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1900-1990; photocopies (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Notes on jurisdiction and Connecticut Indian Affairs Council, 1990-1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians eviction from reservation, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Paucatuck Eastern Pequot Indians public inquiry RE: 1983 Connecticut Indian Affairs Council decision (GMD), circa 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Research, circa 1829-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Research materials, 1841-2000, undated; photocopies (Box 6)
    - Research materials - census records, 1800-1850; photocopies (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Vital records and census records, 1900-1930 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Press Files, 2000-2002
    - Clippings, 2000-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clippings - lobbying, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Maps, 1963-1965
    - Eastern Pequot Indian Ancestry (according to petitions and tribal membership lists), Stonington / North Stonington, Connecticut, undated; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
    - Miner Subdivision, Route 2, Zoned R40, Plan of Properties belonging to Marine B. & W. Lawrence Miner, Jr., Trustees, Ledyard, Connecticut, 1965 December 1; Morris W. Ruoff, Surveryor,; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
    - Plan made for State of Connecticut showing the reservation of the Eastern Tribe of Pequot Indians, Town of North Stonington, Connecticut, 1963 January; Chandler & Palmer, Engineers,; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
      Drawing Number: 189, 191, and 192
- Series 4. Golden Hill Paugussetts, 1708-2006; bulk 1970-2006
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1708-2004
    - Attorney General's Office memorandum to Office of the Solicitor, ex parte submission by Golden Hill Paugussetts - petition for tribal acknowledgment, 1998 April 3 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Brief in Support of the Golden Hill Paugussett Tribe's Request for Reconsideration of the September 26, 1996 Final Determination of the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs of the United States Department of the Interior, 1996 December 24 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1989-2001 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous documents, 1993-2004 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence - Flint, Myles E., esq., 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Freedom of Information Act appeal and objection to Bureau of Indian Affairs refusal to consider material, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence - Initial review of petition for federal acknowledgment, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior preliminary decision RE Golden Hill Paugussett, 1995 May 23 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Exhibit volume I, circa 1973-1992; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
    - Exhibit volume I, petition for federal acknowledgment, 1993 March; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 13-18)
    - Exhibit volume II, circa 1916-1993; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - Exhibit volume II, petition for federal acknowledgment - Mashantucket Pequot Tribe, undated; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 21-23)
    - Exhibit volume V, 1768-1837; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 24-25)
    - Exhibit volume VI, An Ethnohistory of the Paugussett Tribes, 1992; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 26-29)
    - Exhibit volume VII, A Quarter-Acre of Heartache, 1985; photocopies (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Exhibit volume IX, circa 1970-1992; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibit volume X, XI, and XII, circa 1767-1992; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Exhibit volume XIII, 1993; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Exhibit volume un-numbered section, 1708-1992, undated; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 5-8)
    - Exhibits 1-51, 1769-2002, undated; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 9-15)
    - Exhibits 52-67 and related documents on Turkey Hill Indians and identification records, circa 1871-2003; photocopies (Box 8, Folder 16-17)